Previously on Marshals.
Casey, meet my marshals.
Andrew, Miles, Bill.
Welcome to the U.
S.
Marshals.
You got eyes on a possible trigger, man?
Black bag.
David, get me that bomber.
It's okay.
You're okay now.
Dutton's are born with
dysfunction in their blood.
I'm changing paths.
I'm trying to find a new
beginning for me and Tate.
That bang town used to blow
off some steam on the range.
Would you rather spend the
day chasing him or fishing?
Catching more trout
than you is my priority.
Beating you to the river is mine.
Game on.
It's gonna be hard to reel in all
them fish with just your hands.
I got another one.
Want me to pick a fly for you?
I'm just scaring him down to you, son.
Brings back memories.
It's a good day.
What about tomorrow?
Ready to kick doors as a marshal?
I'd be quiet.
Just paperwork and the new guy nonsense.
You sure you're ready for this change?
A new start will do us both good.
But who's gonna look over
East Camp with you working?
Rip found some hands so I could
find a more permanent solution.
That means tomorrow's
your new beginning too.
Good.
So after a day like this, I
know which time can stand still.
So I'm looking over this HVT when Double
G, he walks back into the room dressed in
the clothes of the telly monster we just
swacked.
Hat, pajamas, the whole get up.
Yeah.
18 for the round.
How can you identify me this soon?
He'll tell you.
Oh.
And since neither of us is asleep tonight,
only question is will be my place or
yours?
Yeah, a girl loves to have options.
Really?
Like, should I spray you?
Or stab you?
A little hostile in here tonight.
Especially the bartender.
She's knives out for Cal.
Her name's Maddie, and you're
talking out of your ass.
Pardon.
Ma'am, may I buy you a drink?
Make up for my friend's two left feet.
Ma'am?
My abuela's a ma'am.
No.
Thank you.
This 10 gallon hat wouldn't let him quit.
I mean, it wouldn't kill you
to broaden your horizons.
Come on, find some companionship.
Is that why you have your
war buddy joining the team?
No, look, I brought Casey in for the
same reason I brought both of you on.
Okay, to sharpen the tip of the spear.
The spear's pretty lethal already.
When I go into battle, I need
teammates who have a fight.
Whether it's a tenacious manhunter from
the Bronx, or a former res cop with fire
in his belly.
We just want to make sure your shared past
isn't stepping on our toes in the present.
New team, new dynamic.
Bring to that.
Bringing the smoke today.
Leaving you behind, innit?
Mm-hmm.
Watch this.
Bold move, embarrassing
the boss on the first day.
Double or nothing?
Hell no.
It's the paying off loans from all the
money you took off of me in Afghanistan.
Is this some sort of entry exam?
Nope, just seeing how the lone wolf
is feeling joining the new pack.
A fit man's never been my strong suit.
Well, I know moving forward isn't easy,
but getting back into the fire's gonna do
you right.
Well, then I'll get comfortable
being uncomfortable.
You know what?
I'll let your training day begin.
Tori, gear cleaning.
How else did you guys initiate me?
Come on, we gotta break in the FNG.
You know, why don't we just
welcome Casey as one of us?
I mean, if hunting down those bombers
didn't initiate him, what will?
Non-natives have no
appreciation for tradition.
Hey, since we've all been shot at
together, let's just skip the formalities.
Uh, I'm glad to join this outfit.
See if you say that after the show.
See if you say that after drinking
through a fire hose today.
Yeah, I tread lightly, Miles.
Casey's reasonable until he isn't.
I'd ease him in.
I gotta talk to Harry.
Well, tour's pretty simple.
Head's on now.
Unisex.
It's real intimate.
Cal built this team to model after a SEAL
unit, but he failed to account for certain
differences, like teammates with two X
chromosomes.
We're a toilet seat stays down unit.
Bell runs 10 ship.
Appreciate the intel.
These are the cages.
Huh.
You waiting to move in?
Uh, there's no use decorating
since I'm only passing through.
These bags need reloading, so I'll
do that as you continue the tour.
Here's your day.
Feels like another meeting that could
have been an email, Marshal Gifford.
Deputizing Dutton is one thing, but
making him a member of the team?
Casey turns us into the elite unit that
you envisioned when you just stood this
team up.
Yeah, but you got the
wrong pig by the tail.
A Dutton wearing the Marshal star.
It just doesn't sit right.
He knows the area, he knows the people,
where the bodies are buried, and not to
mention, he's equipped to run any kind of
op this team face.
But you don't find it odd that he's
jumping back into law enforcement when the
two biggest cold cases in this state are
his father's death and his brother's
disappearance?
It's just a coincidence.
There's no such thing as a
coincidence with the Duttons.
Excuse me.
Deputy Marshal Galvin, we have something.
Please.
Ops and investigations run out of here.
I've been busy.
Well, hunting dirtbags
is our bread and butter.
We connect to the fusion center here.
Maintaining two-way intelligence and
information flow is critical to our
mission.
Right.
Don't worry.
You're here to be a gunslinger,
not a pencil pusher.
These are our techs, analysts,
as well as our liaison team.
Our liaisons that work with local,
state, and federal law enforcement.
The lack of infrastructure
forces us to wear many hats.
Especially now that we got
a trouble magnet on board.
Fireplace is subtle.
Compound used to be an old mill.
Cal kept the blast furnace as a reminder
that this unit was forged in the fire.
Okay, buddy, listen up.
CI phoned in ahead on
a fugitive, Raul Garza.
He's a member of the 406
Royals with federal warrants.
Where's he at?
Belgrade Trailer Park.
People there got nothing to lose.
Usually put up the biggest fight.
Always takes us to the best places.
Chock up.
So much for easing you on.
Informant says Garza's car
hasn't moved since last night.
What's he doing here?
This isn't Royals' turf.
Royals blew up 18th Street
Mafia's stash house last month.
Could be expanding the footprint.
Maybe Garza's just
sampling the local product.
Because Matheron's rampant out here.
How many suspects on target?
It's unknown, but hopefully they're
still sleeping or down hard on a bender.
Think a door knock entry?
No.
We're gonna roll Garza
before his eyes even open.
Okay?
Fasten up.
You want me in the stack?
Train the wheels around.
I'm gonna take square to patrol.
Miles, Andrea, you're on me.
Bell, you're outside the casing.
I prefer team entry.
Go slow after taking that round, okay?
You don't know what baggage
you're carrying down the range.
That's exactly why I gotta get
punched in the face and find out.
Come on.
You can swap.
I'll watch Dutton.
Yeah, okay.
Let's move out.
Little eager to jump out of the stack.
First kill weighing on you?
He's in the ground, not in my head.
Uh-huh.
U.
S.
Marshal!
I thought we missed one hell of a party.
Suspect's out breathing death.
He was coming.
He was in for a world of
hurt if he made it to me.
High job.
We're in Montana.
Not a war zone.
Cold habits.
I thought Garza was gonna
alligator roll you, Cal.
I handled my business
just like the rest of you.
It was flawless up.
Nearly flawless.
Popped a damn button
taking that perp down.
Oh, I'll be sure to note your shirt
as a casualty in the after action.
It's just like old times, huh?
Kicking doors and rolling up dirt bags.
Except back then I was on your
six, not on the sidelines.
Excuse me.
Tats on the guy we collared with Garza.
Mark him as a member of the
Aryan Brethren of Idaho.
And the pills he was
holding were fentanyl.
White nationalist and Latin gang leader.
Make an odd couple.
Drugs are a hell of a uniform.
Oh.
Hey, I got a situation on the ranch.
You mind if I go deal with it?
Oh, you didn't get to kick doors, so
you're taking your ball and going home.
Hey, let the DA know about the fentanyl
and send Garza and the Aryan upstate to
Helena, okay?
I'm rolling with Casey.
All right, sorry.
I can take care of it on my own.
Team needs to learn that one is none.
All right.
See y'all.
What business do the Aryans
have with the royal family?
I don't know.
The Aryans were on my radar at ATF.
A group of them were behind the plot
to kidnap the governor of Idaho.
The cattle told us to ship them out.
We're here to wage a war on violence,
not just roll up foot soldiers.
A little digging can't hurt.
The stallion broke clean through.
From man hunting to horse hunting.
Is that the kind of call out
you do, like, as a cow cop?
You may joke.
That horse on the loose is
a grenade with a pin pulled.
That's not a horse.
That's anger with legs.
Yeah.
Something tells me he's
not going to go easy.
I don't know your plan, but I don't
think I can be your QRF on this, pal.
Plan?
I'm making this up as I go.
Casey Dutton, U.
S.
Marshal Harry Gifford, makes me your boss.
It feels like I'm working
for everybody today.
Oh, you two are out gallivanting.
Andrea made a hell of a discovery.
This is the first time I've
ever been on a mission.
I've never been on a mission before.
There's a fentanyl deal going down today
between the Aryans and the 406 Royals.
How'd you put that together?
The Aryan, Lenny Nelson, two-time loser,
he came to Bozeman to let the Royals test
the fentanyl.
Well, they're going to call off that
deal as soon as they realize they're MIA.
Well, Nelson says he and Garza were
just meeting to test the product.
And after they signed off, they let
themselves enjoy a long weekend consuming
product.
And Garza, he backed all that up?
Well, he wasn't as charmed
by Deputy Cruz as Nelson.
You know, the DEA can't spin up and down.
The DEA can't spin up in time to get here.
So we're on agent assist.
FBI chatter says the Aryans
are plotting something big.
Yeah, selling the fentanyl is probably
going to be how they finance it.
Well, this unit was designed
for big game hunting.
I mean, Aryan Brethren would
be quite the trophy on my wall.
Do you have the muscle for that?
Well, Cal sold you his last
piece to his dream team.
Prime chance for you to
back those big words up.
Okay, so where's the deal going down?
Just over the Wyoming border, a
place called the Zone of Death.
I don't know.
Apparently, it got its name because
there's no citizens, no law enforcement,
no judges or juries.
So there's no way to prosecute crimes.
The local legend has been a dumping ground
for the region's most depraved criminals.
There is no way that's true.
Well, it doesn't.
They've been here for over a century.
Does this tale get passed
down through generations?
No, it's the first time I'm hearing of it.
Surveillance cameras in gear.
Rangefinder, too.
I need all the eyes I
can get watching my back.
He's got this deal in his feels.
You undermining me with Harry?
I was finding a fight to
pick like you hired me to do.
I'm still sore from our last ride.
Are the horses my punishment?
No.
Just the best way to keep a low
profile in the Zone of Death.
Well, taking down a deal between two
dangerous gangs doesn't exactly scream low
profile.
That's why we're only busting the air.
And let the royals walk?
They distribute meth to the rez.
Push that fentanyl onto Broken
Rock, it'll spread like wildfire.
Don't worry.
Okay?
See him for the DEA to sweep up.
The Aryans are planning an attack.
They take priority.
Excuse me.
You gotta hand it to her.
I never saw my dad when he was on duty.
Yep, found the balance
that eludes most of us.
She's a remarkable woman.
As a mother.
Mm-hmm.
I was hoping to have a word.
Sir?
You Duttons always had a
soft spot for public service.
Livestock Commission,
Attorney General, Governor.
Just doing our part.
Yeah, but for whom?
Seems to me it was always in service of
your family, or Yellowstone Ranch, or some
form of vengeance.
Well, the Yellowstone's gone.
Same for most of my family.
And as for vengeance,
the day's still young.
You got a sharp tongue,
just like your father.
We had a history, you know.
Yeah, he used to talk about that a lot.
Really?
It's nice of your husband
and kid to drop by.
It was inappropriate during work hours.
It won't happen again.
Are you kidding?
Our family could have swung
by when I was deployed.
I might still have one.
This job keeps me around a lot more
than working undercover with ATF did.
They're just adjusting to the new norm.
I admire you prioritizing your family.
It takes a lot more discipline than I had.
You don't think your husband would stop by
because he's worried you took that round,
though?
If I let him clean teeth,
he lets me fight crime.
You didn't tell him, did you?
You know, building walls shuts out
the people that you care about.
They're not walls.
Zone of death, my ass.
There's nothing out here.
Awful quiet, cowboy.
What's been banging like a powwow
drum since we left Bozeman?
You worried?
Tip of the spear goes where it's pointed.
Even if it's the last
place you want to be.
So you do know this place?
Op just has a lot of unknowns.
Probably got enough of those in your life.
Do you really not know
where your brother Jamie is?
At least when my dad got
killed, we knew he was gone.
Gave us closure.
Family history like yours?
I'm sure it's hard to turn the page.
for a takedown.
Spotty comms, y'all.
Rough terrain, wild animals, and two
violent gangs, so everybody's gotta be
dialed in.
Trackers are prepped
with royals as vehicles.
Better work so the DEA can help them down.
All right, Bell, handle
the trackers and miles.
Andrew and I, we're gonna run surveillance
from that rock outcrop over there.
In case you just watched Bell on mile six.
This'll work for Overwatch.
Interdicting the Aryans
on horses is a tall order.
That's exactly why we're gonna hit them
after the deal when the guard's down,
okay?
Casey, you got me?
Line the dog, drive the plane.
Uh...
Something reflecting across that ravine.
That junk over there.
Aerial ground's more than just a rumor.
It's almost drop time.
Ghosts in the ravine,
they do not concern us.
Move into position, let's go.
Come on, move into
position, let's go, y'all.
Three trucks inbound.
Sensitive windows.
Okay, Bell, target's incoming.
Good copy.
Got eyes on two SUVs coming from the east.
Aryans.
Bell, royals are in the pickups.
Roger that.
Moving into position.
We're hitting.
Got 11 suspects on the ground.
Casey, something's about to pop off.
Everybody's carrying him, but
nobody seems ready to go hot.
Fentanyl's been handed over.
Yeah, where's the cash?
Money exchange should
not be this complicated.
Bell, you're clear to move in position.
We gotta get that truck alive, Bell.
Good copy.
All clear, Bell.
What the hell are they looking at?
Can't ID.
Bell, you got company.
Take cover.
Bell, beat feet.
Bandits camped out on Bell's paws.
The vehicle's blocking my angle.
Miles, move up to cover Bell.
Moving.
Got an issue.
Over.
Miles, are you in position?
I say again, Miles, are you in position?
Bell's just hanging out in the wind.
We gotta get down there.
Okay, Miles, we're up.
Over.
Cal, that royal's right on top of Miles.
The whole point was to avoid
getting into a gunfight.
Andrew's right.
We gotta hold on to what we got.
If we don't move, it's Roaner all over.
Okay, don't engage unless you have to.
What the hell was that?
That's a bomb.
Aryans aren't planning an attack.
They're about to execute one.
Bomb could kill everyone on the ground.
And now it's in the wind.
I can't even get a signal.
Decision to bring horses isn't helping.
Casey, the lead Aryan
SUV is carrying a bomb.
I need you to enter it in.
I need you to lock in, okay?
Breathe, aim low, and squeeze,
otherwise Bell's dead.
All right?
Yeah.
Cover me.
Okay.
Okay, cover Bell.
I'm moving down, all right?
Bell, I'm almost through your balls.
Okay.
Okay, blank him.
Get Bell back into the spot.
Could use Casey's gun right now.
You shoot, I move.
I shoot, you move.
Let's go.
Two rows are moving on you.
That's a good idea.
Okay, I'm gonna move to cover.
You both block the car, so let's go.
Come on.
No, let's cover them.
I'm taking right.
On the ground!
You guys watch those.
Don't move.
On the ground!
Hands behind your back!
Cover.
Hey, guys.
Where's Casey?
It's gonna be slow, and
it's gonna be painful.
Please.
No, didn't make it to Bozeman, and the
bomb didn't make it to the federal
courthouse in Idaho.
Well, Idaho State Police
picked the remaining Aryans up.
One said they were planning on
moving the bomb straight to Target.
You earned your marshal
money today, Casey.
Guess the training wheels are off.
I think, though.
There were five Aryans on Target.
Three were arrested,
one killed in the SUV.
He's on a death, I guess.
Time to baptize Casey.
Tradition.
Non-alcoholic in your case.
Good thing, considering
what he's capable of sober.
Hey.
To Casey.
New guy, no more.
Cheers.
Go, go, go.
My conquering heroes, FBI, ATF, and
Homeland Security are licking my boots
over this win.
Thwarting a domestic terrorist attack?
Can your wall fit a big
game trophy that size?
Shouldn't ease any doubts
you have about Casey.
Because he won us the victory today.
Giving credit to the guy who
overruled you on the battlefield.
Dunn was insubordinate.
There's a surprise.
Best idea wins on my team.
Did Casey run roughshod over Cal?
No.
He was quiet before things got kinetic.
Like he had something on his mind?
His own agenda, perhaps?
I don't know.
But when I brought up his
brother, he got spooked.
Casey doesn't spook.
Maybe he does when he's hiding something.
Like what?
For keeping us off the scent
of his fugitive brother.
If he joined this unit for some nefarious
reasons, I'm not going to let him get away
with it.
Now, who's doing the after action?
I'll do it.
You all right?
Guy killed still in my head.
I know I'm the real new guy here.
I wish I could be the new guy again.
I didn't freeze up out there.
My people think killing a
Rattler is a transgression.
Bad omen, even.
There's always going to be a snake.
You can't reason with it
or hope it'll back down.
Gotta be more dangerous than it
is or this job may not be for you.
That's okay.
I thought our six-play battle was going
to be the most intense action today.
What was that about us
not being in a war zone?
Back in the teams.
I could always count on you
being dialed in downrange.
You seemed a little bit out
of it when we got on target.
Yeah.
Grappling with some skeletons I'm
trying to keep in my family's closet.
Operate when you got
ghosts hanging over you.
And there was definitely one on the op.
Ruiner.
Bring them up like that, it's just...
A cheap shot.
It wasn't a cheap shot,
it was a targeted one.
It kept history from it beating itself.
I guess Stutton's known as
the Monopoly and Scout, right?
One second, you're backing me.
The next case, he's calling the shots.
Wouldn't be sitting there if
Casey hadn't taken action.
No, that is not my issue.
Your war buddy manipulating
you in the heat of battle is.
What does Ruiner mean, anyway?
Why don't we focus on your
shotting intel instead?
Well, it would look a whole lot different
right now if I hadn't uncovered that deal.
Those attaboys you got from
Gifford and gave to Casey?
They should have been for me.
Oh, I see.
Gifford, you take it
back to your old team,
and you're just upset because you
didn't get the credit you deserve.
Is that how it works?
This is compliments of the cowboy.
He says, sorry, ma'am.
Want to hear some more SEAL stories?
I'm going.
You're a brave man coming back for more.
A cowboy worth his salt gets
right back on the horse.
Especially when chasing
something as health-bred as you.
I can't promise I won't buck a gun.
I'm counting on it.
Who knew playing Cupid would
have you like pig and slop?
This chair's empty if
you've got a minute to chat.
I'd like to share more than
just war stories with you.
You want more than a minute.
But I don't have that to give.
Hey, thought you'd be
prioritizing your family.
And expose them to what I'm
carrying away from today?
You know, when I was operating,
the battlefield was
thousands of miles from home.
Gave me a chance to shed
some of the toxins from war.
Yeah, Buffer Zone sounds
real nice right about now.
Nice job.
You've got to find a way
to let go of a fighter
that people care about and let go of us.
So you're saying drinking with
you is in the best interest
of my family?
Better get you to step.
Where you been?
Reinforcing the corrals.
More things change.
How'd it go today?
Yeah, Yellowstone might be gone,
but there's still some
landmines left behind.
How about you?
I don't know.
I didn't find my new beginning.
They'll find you.
When?
When you're ready.
I went and saw Grandpa Long today.
He wants us to honor Mom at
the Remembrance Ceremony.
Next month.
Sure.
Asked about borrowing
your favorite necklace.
Any idea where it is?
I'll look tomorrow.
Spent too much time worried
about buried treasure today.